Guide to the Sholem Asch Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1923-1956; Series II; 0.4; (1 box)
  - "D" general, 1930-32 (Box 14, Folder 155)
    Dubnov, Simon
    Dullin, Charles
    Letter is addressed to Edmond Fleg
  - "E" general, 1932-35 (Box 14, Folder 156)
    Edinburgh Jewish Community
    Einstein, Albert
    Includes letter to Mr. Vladeck
  - Educational and cultural organizations, 1931-40, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 157)
    Includes letters from Yiddish Art
    Theatre, Yiddish Scientific
    Institute, The Hebrew Theatre,
    Theatre Artistique Juif
  - "F" general, 1931-43 (Box 14, Folder 158)
    Finkelstein, Louis
    Freid, M. J.
    French, Robert Dudley
  - Fefer, Itzik
    See: Solomon Michoels, Box 14, folder 164
  - "G" general, 1930-43 (Box 14, Folder 159)
    Glücksmann, Helene and Heinrich
    Gollancz, Victor
    Good, Edward
    Goodenough, Erwin Ramsdell
  - "H" general, 1930-38, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 160)
    Herterich, Franz
    Hirschbein, Peretz
    Horch, Alice
    Horonczyk, Simeon
    Huddleston, Sisley
    Includes letter to Mrs. Asch
  - "J" general, 1936-49, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 161)
    Jackan, S.
    Joffe, L.
  - Jewish Daily Forward
    See: Abraham Cahan, Box 14, folder 154, Baruch Vladeck, Box 14, folder 171
  - "K" general, 1934-37, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 162)
    Kaplan, S. A.
    Katzenelson, Berl
    Kesten, Hermann
    Kraut, J. [?]
    Letter is addressed to unidentified
    "Monsieur"
  - Knollenberg, Bernhard
  - "L" general, 1932-40 (Box 14, Folder 163)
    Leftwich, Joseph
    LeHand, Marguerite A.
    Lehman, Herbert H.
    Lewisohn, T. S.
    Lewisohn, T. and Ludwig
    Lowenthal, Marvin
  - Liessin, Abraham
    See: Abraham Walt, Box 14, folder 172
  - "M" general, 1932-43, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 164)
    Mahler, Alma and Franz Werfel
    Mann, Thomas
    Meier-Graefe, Julius
    Meier-Graefe, Ada
    Michoels, Solomon and Isaac Feffer
    Moll, Carl
    Muret, Maurice
  - "N" general, 1937, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 165)
    Narkis, M.
    Neumann, Alfred
  - Nemoy, Leon
  - Niger, Samuel
    See: Samuel Charney, Box 14, folder 154
  - Oyved, Moyshe
    See: Edward Good, Box 14, folder 159
  - "P" general, 1923-36 (Box 14, Folder 166)
    Polish Ambassador in France
    Polish Legation
    Prilutzki, Zvi
  - PEN clubs, 1928-38 (Box 14, Folder 167)
    Dubrovnik
    Brussels
    Budapest
    Includes letter addressed to Stefan
    Zweig
    London
    Prague
    Vilna
    Warsaw
  - "R" general, 1932-44 (Box 14, Folder 168)
    Rabinowitz, Louis Mayer
    Reisen, Abraham
    Romains, Jules
    Rosenwald, William
    Roth, Josef
    Rothschild, Lionel Walter
  - "S" general, 1916-40, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 169)
    Salten, Felix
    Samuel, Edwin
    Schickele, René
    Schiff, Jacob H.
    Schneiderman, Harry
    Schneur, Salman
    Schorr, Moses
    Schumacher, S.
    Schwarzbard, Dr.
    Schwarzbard, Shalom
    Scott, Catharine Amy Dawson
    Skandinavisk Jodisk Ungdomsforbund
    Stawek, Walery
    Spire, André
  - Tunkel, Jacob, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 170)
  - Vladeck, Baruch, 1932-37 (Box 14, Folder 171)
  - "W" general, 1927-47, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 172)
    Walt, Abraham
    Warburg, Felix
    Wasserman, Jakob
    Weizmann, Chaim
    Werfel, Franz
    See also: Alma Mahler, Box 14, folder 164
    Wise, Stephen Samuel
    Witherspoon, M. M.
    Witherspoon, Margaret
    Witkacy, Tuoj [?]
    Wittlin, J.
  - Yale University Library, 1939-56 (Box 14, Folder 173-174)
    Babb, James T.
    Addressed to Mrs. Asch
    Knollenberg, Bernhard
    Nemoy, Leon
  - "Z" general, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 175)
    von Zsolnay, Andy
    von Zsolnay, Anna and Paul
  - Zweig, Stefan, 1929-41 (Box 14, Folder 176)
  - On his 50th birthday, 1930-31 (Box 14, Folder 177-179)
  - Unidentified, 1940-43 (Box 14, Folder 180)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Bon Voyage telegrams, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 181)
    - Visiting cards, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 182)
- Photographs, 1907-1943; Series III; 0.4; (1 box)
  Photographs is arranged by subject.
  - PEOPLE
    - Sholem Asch, 1939, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 183-184)
      Stored also in: Oversize, Box 17,
      folder 237
    - Sholem Asch with others, 1930-43, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 185-186)
      folders 238-239
    - Friends of Sholem Asch, 1907-33, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 187-188)
      folder 240
    - Postcard photographs -- friends of Sholem Asch (Box 15, Folder 189)
  - PLACES AND OBJECTS
    - Illuminated manuscript by Artur Szyk, Jus Polonicum. Jura Judaeis per Boleslaum ducem Maioris Poloniae ann. 1264 concessa., [1927] (Box 15, Folder 190)
    - Jewish antiquities at Worms, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 191)
    - Jewish antiquities, various places in Europe, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 192)
    - Jewish art objects, manuscripts and books owned by Asch (Box 15, Folder 193)
    - Jewish art objects owned by Ludwig Lewisohn, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 194)
    - Views of Palestine, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 195-196)
- Other Papers, 1927-1943; Series IV; 0.25; (1 box)
  Other Papers is arranged by format and then by
  subject. The bust by Morice Lipsi is housed separately in
  art storage.
  - CLIPPINGS
    - Portraits of Sholem Asch, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 197)
    - Portraits of Sholem Asch with others, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 198)
      folder 241
    - Portraits of friends of Sholem Asch (Box 16, Folder 199)
      folder 242
    - Miscellaneous material relating to Asch's life and work, 1928-43
    - Speeches, essays, interviews about Asch, 1930-43 (Box 16, Folder 200)
      Stored also in: Oversize, Box 23,
      folder 281 and bsd, folder 285
    - Sholem Asch's 50th birthday, 1930-31
    - Sholem Asch's 60th birthday, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 201)
  - POSTCARDS
    - Places and Objects
      - Book of postcards of National Museum, Bezalel, Jerusalem, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 202)
      - Business life and costumes in Syria and Palestine (Box 16, Folder 203)
      - Jewish antiquities at Worms, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 204-205)
      - Jewish antiquities in Europe, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 206)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 207)
  - ARTWORK
    - Bust of Sholem Asch by Morice Lipsi. Bronze, 38 cm., 1927
      Signed Moryce Lipchytz
    - Sketches of Sholem Asch by Hermann Struck, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 208)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - Biographical and bibliographical notes about Sholem Asch (Box 16, Folder 209)
    - Invitations and programs to Asch's 50th birthday celebration, 1931 (Box 16, Folder 210)
    - Press release about Asch and the Joint Distribution Committee (Box 16, Folder 211)
    - Programs for PEN club meetings, 1929-30 (Box 16, Folder 212)
    - Corsage worn by Mrs. Asch at the celebration of Sholem Asch's birthday in Paris?, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 212a)
- Oversize, 13; (7 boxes)
  Oversize contains two types of materials. There are
  pages from the Writings series, each identified by
  title and the box and folder from which it was removed, and
  replaced by a reference photocopy. There are also oversize
  items not replaced by reference photocopies, including two
  major parts of two novels in the Writings series. The
  bust by Morice Lipsi is housed separately in art storage.
  The materials are listed in box order.
  - Baym Opgrunt (The War Goes On), box 1, folder 2 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 213)
  - Baym Opgrunt (The War Goes On), box 1, folder 5 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 214)
  - Baym Opgrunt (The War Goes On), box 1, folder 6 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 215)
  - Baym Opgrunt (The War Goes On), box 1, folder 7 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 216)
  - Baym Opgrunt (The War Goes On), box 1, folder 8 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 217)
  - Baym Opgrunt (The War Goes On), box 1, folder 9 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 218)
  - Dray Shtet (Three Cities), box 2, folder 17 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 219)
  - Dray Shtet (Three Cities), box 3, folder 25 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 220)
  - Dray Shtet (Three Cities), box 3, folder 27 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 221)
  - Dray Shtet (Three Cities), box 3, folder 28 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 222)
  - Dray Shtet (Three Cities), box 3, folder 31 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 223)
  - Der Man fun Notseres (The Nazarene) Part I: Box 5, folder 45 (from Series I) (Box 17, Folder 224)
  - Der Man fun Notseres (The Nazarene) Part I: Box 5, folder 47 (from Series I) (Box 17, Folder 225)
  - Der Sheliekh (The Apostle) Part II: Box 7, folder 74 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 226)
  - Der Sheliekh (The Apostle) Part II: Box 7, folder 75 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 227)
  - Der Sheliekh (The Apostle) Part II: Box 7, folder 76 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 228)
  - Der Sheliekh (The Apostle) Part III: Box 8, folder 80 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 229)
  - Toyt Urteyl (Death Sentence) Box 9, folder 88 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 230)
  - Vos Ikh Gloyb (What I Believe) Box 9, folder 91 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 231)
  - Vos Ikh Gloyb (What I Believe) Box 9, folder 92 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 232)
  - Vos Ikh Gloyb (What I Believe) Box 9, folder 93 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 233)
  - Vos Ikh Gloyb (What I Believe) Box 9, folder 94 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 234)
  - Got fun Nekome ( God of Vengeance ) Playbill for Apollo production (from Series I), [1923] (Box 17, Folder 234a-b)
  - "In the Valley of Death," The New York Times Magazine (from Series I), 1943 Feb 7 (Box 17, Folder 235)
  - "Shoen Gekredentst dem Tish" Box 13, folder 147 (from Series I), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 236)
  - Photographs of Sholem Asch (from Series III), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 237)
  - Photographs of Sholem Asch with others (from Series III), 1930, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 238-239)
  - Photographs of friends of Sholem Asch (from Series III), 1907-33 (Box 17, Folder 240)
  - Clippings - Portraits of Sholem Asch with others (from Series IV), 1936, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 241)
  - Clippings - Portraits of friends of Sholem Asch (from Series IV) (Box 17, Folder 242)
  - Baym Opgrunt (The War Goes On), Advertisements (from Series I), 1936 (Box 18, Folder 243)
  - Baym Opgrunt (The War Goes On), Reviews (from Series I), 1936-37 (Box 18, Folder 244)
  - Dray Shtet (Three Cities) Advertisements (from Series I), 1933 (Box 18, Folder 245)
  - Dray Shtet (Three Cities) Reviews (from Series I), 1931-37 (Box 18, Folder 246)
  - Dray Shtet (Three Cities) Reviews of Petersburg (from Series I), 1929-30 (Box 18, Folder 247)
  - Gots Gefangene (Prisoners of God) Reviews (from Series I), 1932 (Box 18, Folder 248)
  - Der Man fun Notseres (The Nazarene) Reviews (from Series I), 1939 (Box 18, Folder 249)
  - Mottke the Thief Advertisements (from Series I), [1933-35] (Box 18, Folder 250)
  - Mottke the Thief Reviews (from Series I), 1935 (Box 18, Folder 251)
  - Dray Shtet (Three Cities) Scrapbook of reviews (from Series I), 1933 (Box 19, Folder 259)
  - Der Man fun Notseres (The Nazarene) Part III, holograph, corrected (from Series I), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 261-270b)
  - Der Sheliekh (The Apostle) Part I, holograph, corrected (from Series I), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 271-279)
  - Der Sheliekh (The Apostle) Advertisements (from Series I), 1943 (Box 22, Folder 252)
  - Der Sheliekh (The Apostle) Reviews (from Series I), 1943 (Box 22, Folder 253)
  - Der Tehilim Yid (Salvation) Advertisements (from Series I), 1934 (Box 22, Folder 254)
  - Der Tehilim Yid (Salvation) Reviews (from Series I), 1934 (Box 22, Folder 255)
  - Children of Abraham Reviews (from Series I), 1942 (Box 22, Folder 256)
  - Got fun Nekome ( God of Vengeance ) Playbills (from Series I), [1923] (Box 22, Folder 257)
  - Reviews (from Series I), 1929-43 (Box 22, Folder 258)
  - Miscellaneous clippings relating to Asch's life and work (from Series IV), 1928-43 (Box 23, Folder 280)
  - Clippings - speeches, essays and interviews by and about Sholem Asch (from Series IV), 1930-43 (Box 23, Folder 281)
  - Clippings - Sholem Asch's 50th birthday (from Series IV), 1930-31 (Box 23, Folder 282)
  - Yoysef (Joseph) Box 11, folder 111 (from Series I), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 283)
  - "A Briv tsu di Panes fun Poyln" Box 12, folder 121 (from Series I), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 284)
  - Clippings - speeches, essays and interviews by and about Sholem Asch (from Series IV), 1930-43 (Box bsd, folder 285)
  - Bust of Sholem Asch by Morice Lipsi. Bronze, 38 cm. (from Series IV), 1927 (Box art, Folder 286)